Paul Field Sifton and Claire Sifton Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File of Paul Field Sifton, 1934-1971 (Box 12-37)
  - Personnel, loyalty, and medical files (Box 37)
    - 1920s-1960s, personnel files [PFS] in print, near-print, and clipping forms
- Writings File, 1922-1968 (Box 38-56)
  Plays in multiple stages of their composition and production, as well as press reaction and research and background material. Also includes material on the "Revolting Playwrights" movement (1935). Poems of Paul Sifton start in the post-World War I period, and end with To the Dallas Underpass (1965). Both Siftons are represented in newspaper and magazine articles; short stories; and book reviews. Book projects of Paul Sifton include an unpublished autobiographical novel (1922); an expose of John L. Lewis (1943); and a proposed work on fisheries in the Third World (1962).
  - Plays (Box 38)
    - [1922], Corn [PFS], one-act play
    - [1925], Oil! [PFS], a futurity
    - 1927, The Belt [PFS]
      - Prompting copy
      - Director's copy
      - Marked printer's copy
    - 1928, The American Beauty [PFS and CGS] (2 copies)
    - [1928-1929], The Break [PFS and CGS], a mass play
    - [1929-1930], Three skits [PFS and CGS]
    - [1930], Jane Daugherty [PFS and CGS], later White Savage, rough drafts
    - [1930], Jane Daugherty [PFS and CGS], typescript
    - [1930-1931], White Savage, screenplay by PFS and John P. Fort
    - 1930, Glory [PFS and CGS], revised version (2 copies) (Box 39)
    - 1930, Midnight [PFS and CGS]
      - Early version, "Night of the Execution"
      - Second version, "In the Meantime"
      - Marked rehearsal copy
      - Theatre Guild version
      - Reading version
    - 1931-1933, 1931--- [PFS and CGS] (Box 40)
      - Early version, "Son of God"
      - Production version
      - German versions I and II, (2 folders)
      - French version
      - Reworkings for Interludes
    - 1932, Riviera Blue [PFS and CGS]
      - Early draft version
      - Acting typescript
    - 1932, American Beauty [PFS and CGS], formerly "Revolt in the Castle"
    - 1932, The Mayor's Husband [PFS and CGS], formerly "The Woman Complex," screenplay, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - [1932], The Killer Who Laughed [PFS and CGS], screenplay
      - Early version
      - Corrected script
    - 1933, Blood on the Moon [PFS and CGS]
      - New York version
      - Los Angeles version
      - French version
    - [1933-1934], My Country 'Tis of Thee [PFS and CGS], screenplay
    - 1934, The Drift [PFS and CGS]
      - Early version, "Red Kate"
      - Corrected typescript
      - Corrected script (Box 42)
      - Blocking (production) script
      - Final typescript
      - Reading version
    - 1934, Midnight; screenplay by Chester Erskine
    - 1936, Credits [PFS and CGS], a sketch
    - 1936, Give All Thy Terrors to the Wind [PFS and CGS], one-act play
      - Rough draft
      - Corrected typescript
      - As printed in New Theatre and Film Magazine (January 1938)
    - 1936, The Crime of the Century [PFS and CGS] (Box 43)
      - Rough drafts, (2 folders)
      - Corrected typescript
      - Later typescript
    - 1937, The Doctors [PFS and CGS], one-act play
      - Rough drafts, (2 folders)
      - Corrected typescript
      - Director's copy (Box 44)
      - Final acting script
    - 1937, Hannibal Had Elephants [PFS and CGS], typescript
    - 1938, Kate Larsen [PFS and CGS], one-act play
    - 1939, notes on brief plays [CGS]
    - 1939, Second Honeymoon [CGS], one-act play, rough draft and typescript
    - 1939, Boys Will Be Boys [CGS], one-act play, rough draft and typescript
    - 1939, Kilowatt [CGS], one-act play, corrected typescript
    - 1939, Ernie [CGS], one-act play, corrected and final typescripts
    - 1939, Night and the Road Before Them [CGS], blackout
    - 1939, untitled one-act political play [PFS], rough draft and typescript
    - 1940, Michael [PFS and CGS]
      - Rough drafts, (2 folders)
      - Corrected typescript (Box 45)
      - Ribbon typescript
    - 1948-1950, The Girdle of Venus [PFS and CGS]
      - Typescript
      - Ribbon copy
    - Press notices, background, etc. (Box 46)
      - 1927, The Belt
        - Background
        - Press notices
      - 1930, Midnight, press notices
      - 1931, 1931—, press notices
      - 1931-1933, 1931—, press notices, background
      - 1932-1934, press notices, miscellany
      - 1934-1936, Blood on the Moon, press notices
      - 1935, background of the "Revolting Playwrights," Theatre Guild picketed by PFS and Virgil Ceddes, new dramatists' organizations
      - 1937-1938, Give All Thy Terrors to the Wind, photographs, miscellany
      - 1938-1939, The Doctors, press notices
    - Miscellany (Box 47)
      - 1920s, thoughts on producers [PFS], playlet, "Same to You"
      - 1929-1956, agreements
      - 1938, Kate Larsen [PFS and CGS], printed in One Act Play Magazine (June-July 1938)
      - 1940, Ernie [CGS], printed in One Act Play Magazine and Theatre Review (Jan. 1940)
      - 1940s-1960s, research material for The Girdle of Venus
      - Undated
        - Praise for her theatrical agent [CGS]
        - Fragments
  - Poems [PFS], other writings (Box 48)
    - 1920s, poems [PFS]
    - 1942-1965, poems [PFS]
    - 1965, To the Dallas Underpass [PFS]
      - Revisions, (2 folders)
      - Final version
    - 1920s
      - Book review [PFS]
      - Articles and drafts [PFS] on Menckenism
      - Articles [PFS] on ethics of Pulitzers, newspapers
      - Articles and drafts [PFS] on Elizabeth Gurley Flynn
      - Articles [PFS] for the New York World
      - Articles [PFS] fragments
    - [1927], article [CGS] on fashion
    - 1920s, David [CGS], short story
    - 1931-1935, short stories and articles [PFS and CGS] (Box 49)
    - [1932-1933], article [CGS and Ruth Esther Howe], Little Woman, What Now?
    - 1933
      - Book project [PFS] Notes on America, with early titles
      - A Nose for News [PFS], short story
    - 1933-1935, articles [PFS] on current events
    - 1935, articles [PFS] on the Theatre Guild and on Broadway, part of the "Revolting Playwrights" movement
    - 1930s, book reviews [CGS], drafts
    - 1938-1939, articles, short stories [CGS] on Washington, D.C.
    - 1938-1939, Even the Least of These [CGS], short story
    - 1940, articles [PFS] on current events (Box 50)
    - 1941-1942, articles [PFS] on current events
    - 1945-1946, article [PFS] on General Motors strike and 1931---
    - 1946, article [PFS], Porkchoppers and Democracy, multiple versions and correspondence
    - 1946, book project [PFS], “After Truman, What?,” a book proposal
    - 1940s Writings [PFS], miscellaneous
    - 1950s Writings [PFS], miscellaneous
    - 1964-1968, articles [PFS] on mankind's future
    - Undated, fragments [PFS]
  - Book projects [PFS] (Box 51)
    - [1922] “More Stripes Than Stars,” autobiographical novel
      - Typescript, pages 1-366, (2 folders)
      - Corrected typescript, pages 1-281 only
    - 1943, “Who Are John L. Lewis?” (Box 52)
      - Rough drafts
      - Early typescript
      - Working carbons
      - Clean typescript (Box 53)
      - Corrected typescript; emendations
      - Research material
      - Working references (Box 54)
      - Correspondence
      - References to United Mine Workers
      - Research material
      - Miscellany (research material, near-print, typescript, etc.)
    - 1962, project on fish, fisheries, and the Third World (Box 55)
  - Manuscript and published items (Box 56)
    - 1920s, article [PFS] on farm cooperative bill
    - [1932], short story [PFS], The Big Noise
    - 1934, play [PFS], The Town That Turned Back
    - 1936, article [PFS] on baseball
    - 1941, short story [PFS and CGS] “The Washington Story,” with drafts and correspondence
    - 1941-1942, article [PFS] for Life magazine on “Main Street and the Freedom of the Seas"
    - 1945-1947, articles [PFS] for Labor Press Associates' Washington Report
    - [1952], draft speech [PFS] for James B. Carey, president of the International Union of Electrical Workers
    - 1925-1941, published articles [PFS and CGS], tearsheets, clippings, etc.
    - 1932-1939, published articles [PFS and CGS] in magazines and pamphlets
- Personal Files, 1963 (Box 57-58)
  Material assembled for a testimonial dinner given to Paul Sifton in Washington, D.C., April 23, 1963. Includes a bound volume of presented letters; a larger group of letters not included in the volume; photographs taken at the dinner; notes, remarks, and miscellany. One container has photocopies of letters presented to Sifton.
  - Testimonial dinner to PFS (Box 57)
    - Bound volume of presented letters
    - Letters not included in bound volume
    - Photographs
    - Remarks, notes, miscellany
    - Photocopies of letters sent to PFS, (3 folders) (Box 58)
- Printed Matter, 1919-1971 (Box 59-65)
  Clippings, near-print itesm, pamphlets, and issue-oriented material that reflect Paul Sifton's newspaperman's instinct for the preservation of his sources. Notable groups include post-World War II issues (price decontrol, inflation, atomic energy, full employment, and civil rights); material on the United Automobile Workers; and scrapbooks on John L. Lewis and the United Mine Workers. The latter complement a book project (1943) in the Writings File.
  - Clippings (Box 59)
    - 1919-1950s, (5 folders)
    - 1960s (Box 60)
    - 1940s-1960s, clippings on the UAW-CIO, (3 folders)
  - Pamphlets (Box 61)
    - 1920s-1930s, (2 folders)
    - 1937 Steel Labor; The Progressive
    - 1960s
  - Various subjects (Box 62)
    - 1940s-1950s, un-American activities and anti-communism issues
    - 1940s-1950s, farm labor issues
    - 1945-1946, atomic and postwar issues
    - 1945-1946, price decontrols and inflation
    - 1940s-1950s, natural resources
    - 1950s, civil rights issues and Rule 22 fight in Congress
    - 1960-1961, Citizens' Research Foundation, reports
  - Foreign policy issues, includes United Nations press releases on Dominican and Congo situations, 1961-1962, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - UAW-CIO
    - 1944-1945, (2 folders)
    - 1945-1946, anti-UAW-CIO propaganda
    - 1946-1947, (2 folders)
    - 1948-1957, (6 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1958, including Kohler strike testimony
    - 1959
    - 1961, includes textile workers' strikes (Box 65)
    - 1962-1971, (3 folders)
    - Undated, (2 folders)
  - Photocopied clippings in scrapbooks regarding John L. Lewis and the United Mine Workers Union, 1935, 1938-1939 See Oversize
- Miscellany, 1920s-1980 (Box 66-73)
  Material reflects Paul Sifton's post-retirement interests; also includes obituary, funeral, and condolence files, photographs, press cards, address files, Sifton family items, Sifton genealogy (Canadian), and other items.
  Arranged by topic or type of material.
  - Post-retirement interests [PGS] (Box 66)
    - Plans for Ragged Island, Maine
    - Homes and houses
    - Inventions (new and proposed): "Bubble curtain" and "Electronic Bumblebee"
    - Health aids, especially emphysema
    - Electric wheel
    - Hydrofoils, pontoons, and amphibious boats (Box 67)
    - Electric cars, (3 folders)
    - Batteries
    - Windchargers
    - Vehicles, alternative, (2 folders) (Box 68)
    - Boats, (3 folders)
    - Engines, marine and other, (3 folders) (Box 69)
    - Fish, fisheries, and the Third World, (3 folders)
    - Pollution, man, and the environment, (3 folders) (Box 70)
    - Fragments, notes, (3 folders)
  - Condolences; other materials (Box 71)
    - 1972, obituaries [PFS], New York and Washington, D.C., funeral service, other materials
    - 1972, condolences [PFS], (2 folders)
    - 1980, obituaries [CGS], Washington, D.C., New York, and Mexico
    - 1980, condolences [CGS], (2 folders)
    - 1920s-1960s, retained work of others
  - Photographs, addresses, and miscellany (Box 72)
    - Photographs
      - Of the Siftons
      - Of others
    - Passport, press passes, and calling cards
    - Address book and loose addresses
    - Miscellaneous
  - Sifton family, including genealogy (Canadian), (3 folders) (Box 73)
- Addition, 1923-1948 (Box 74-78)
  Typescripts of articles, books, and other writings, and miscellany. Includes first and authors' editions of the Siftons' plays and books.
  Chronologically arranged.
  - “Panorama” (novel) by CGS, a tale of small-town Missouri from the 1850s to the 1920s [1925-1927] (Box 74)
  - “Untitled” (novel) by CGS,a novel about the "Young People" of the 1920s with (some autobiographical overtones) [1927-1928?]
  - “A Week in the Country” (short novel) by CGS, on contemporary manners and mores of Americans, 1931
  - "The Washington Story" [current history as reportage], by CGS, alternate title: "A Woman's Eye View of the New Deal," 1939 [with irregular pagination]) (Box 75)
  - Hell Is A-Popping (one-act play) by CGS, 1942-1943
  - Spring in Minnesota (play) by PFS and CGS
  - The E.M.I.C. Story [Emergency Maternity and Infant Care program, World War II], typescript report, prepared by CGS for the U.S. Children's Bureau (then in the Department of Labor), 1940-1944 (Box 76)
  - Distribution (a textbook for high school seniors) by CGS, written for the National Education Association, typescript (carbon), 1946-1948
  - The Belt ( 1927 ) play by PFS, two first editions of the book version (Box 77)
    - No. 1, inscribed to CGS' mother, with raison d'etre for the drama
    - No. 2, inscribed to CGS with clippings pertaining to the Ford Motor Co. "speed-up" system, the subject of the play
  - The Perfect Baby ( 1929 ) book by CGS, pseudonym "Claire Morton" used by the author
  - 1931----A Play ( 1931 ) by CGS and PFS, bound authors' copy of the printed version with complete original Broadway cast listed
  - "Give All Thy Terrors to the Wind" ( 1937 ), one-act play by CGS and PFS, printed in The Best Short Plays of the Social Theatre, edited by William Kozlenko (New York, Random House, 1939); play's subject is barratry, in this case the sinking of a ship for the insurance (Box 78)
  - The Wave of the Future ( November 25, 1940 ) book by Anne Morrow Lindbergh; copy retained and annotated by CGS and PFS to document Mrs. Lindbergh's pro-Nazi sentiments
  - Selected Poems for Young People ( 1929 ) by Edna St. Vincent Millay, obtained by CGS and PFS after their purchase (1951) of Ragged Island, Millay's summer home
  - The Harp-Weaver and Other Poems (first edition, 1923 ) by Edna St. Vincent Millay; CGS and PFS were given this work by Agnes Inglis (enclosed card explains provenance)
- Oversize, 1929-1942 (Box OV 1-OV 2)
  Photocopies of clippings in scrapbooks.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Printed matter (Box OV 1)
    - Photocopied clippings in scrapbooks regarding John L. Lewis and the United Mine Workers Union
      - 1929, 1935-1942, (2 vols.) (Container 65)
      - 1935-1940, (2 vols.) (Container 65) (Box OV 2)